先生 对于国防部来说...
Gentlemen,this may only be an exercise...
...这不过是个练习
...so far as the Ministry of Defense is concerned.
但对我来说00部队 被挑选作试验...
But for me, it is a matter of pride...
...实在是光荣的事 这次行动
...that the 00-section has been chosen for this test.
你们负责渗入 直布罗陀的雷达装置
Your objective is to penetrate the radar installations of Gibraltar.
特种航空队已经高度戒备要拦截
The SAS have been placed on full alert to intercept you.
但我知道你们不会让我失望
But I know you won't let me down.
祝你好运
Good luck, men.
糟了!
Oh, blast!
该死的!
Damn!
好了 老友 你出局了
That's it, chum. You're out of it.
游戏玩完了
Game's up, mate.
你死了
You're dead.
不要!
No!
停止!
Halt!
抓牢一点 不然你死定了
Hold on,you're dead!
这里好闷 玛戈
It's all so boring here, Margo.
这里只有一些花花公子和网球手
There's nothing but playboys and tennis pros.
希望我可以找到真正的男子汉
If only I could find a real man.
我要用你的电话 她会再打电话给你
I need to use your phone. She'll call you back.
- 你是谁?  - 詹姆斯邦德
- Who are you? - Bond. James Bond.
控制中心 我是007
Exercise Control, 007 here.
一小时后我再报告
I'll report in an hour.
要加入我吗?
Won't you join me?
两个小时好了
Better make that two.
《007系列之黎明生机》
百提斯拉瓦 捷克斯拉夫
BRATISLAVA, CZECHOSLOVAKIA
我是桑德斯 维也纳第五队队长 你迟到了
Saunders, head of Section V,Vienna. You're bloodv late.
我们来执行任务 不是参加舞会
This is a mission, not a fancy dress ball.
还有时间
We have time.
要保护的人呢?
Where's our man?
在包厢里 在KGB保镖的中间
In the box, between the KGB minders.
好漂亮的女大提琴手
Lovely girl with the cello.
暂时别看女孩
Forget the ladies for once.
科斯克夫在中厂会离开
Koskov will leave the concert at the interval.
我们最好离开吧
We'd better go.
把灯关掉
Turn off the light.
让我们先互相沟通一下
Let's understand one another, Bond.
科斯克夫上将是KGB的主脑
General Koskov is a top KGB mastermind.
是他联络我的 他变节是我的主意
His defection is my baby. He contacted me.
每一个细节都是我策划的
I've planned this out to the last detail.
我以为你会用软头的
You'll want the soft-nosed ones, I expect.
不 我用钢头的
No,the steel-tipped.
KGB狙击手通常会穿防弹衣
KGB snipers usually wear body armor.
你的逃亡路线是怎么样的?
What's your escape route?
对不起
Sorry, old man.
第二十六章第五段说明
Section 26, paragraph 5.
只有在必要情况下才会说出资料
That information is on a need-to-know basis only.
相信你会明白
I'm sure you understand.
科斯克夫受到KGB的严密监管
Koskov is under intensive KGB surveillance.
有狙击手要杀他
A sniper has been assigned to watch him...
他指定要你保护他
...and he expressly asked for you to protect him.
为什么是我?
Why me?
他认为你是最好的特务
He's under the impression you're the best.
车子在哪里?
Where's the car?
在后面的巷子里
In the allev, out the back.
拿椅子来
Bring the chair.
他要用十秒时间来到这里
It'll take him about 10 seconds to reach us.
足够让狙击手取他的命
Plentv of time for a sniper to make strawberry jam of him.
是科斯克夫
There's Koskov.
他在等什么?
What's he waiting for?
狙击手 楼上两层   中间的窗
Sniper. Two floors up. Center window.
拉大提琴的女孩
The girl with the cello.
开枪吧! 邦德!
Fire, Bond! Fire!
向她开火吧! 还等什么?
Shoot her! what are you waiting for?
你故意打不中她
You missed. Deliberately.
- 他在哪里?  - 在行李箱
- Where is he? - In the boot.
- 他们首先会找那里 - 我的逃生路线!
- First place they'd look. - My escape route!
取消
Scrubbed.
到前面去
Get in the front.
詹姆斯邦德
James. James Bond!
晚点再说 上将
Later, general.
摆脱他们
Lose them.
我在边境接你 二十三点 别迟到
I'll pick you up at the border, 23:00 hours. Be there.
你要带他到哪里去?
Where are you taking him?
对不起 第二十六章第五段说明 不能随便透露
Sorry, old man. Section 26, paragraph 5, need-to-know.
我想你也明白
Sure you understand.
- 狙击手是个女的 - 我注意到了
- The sniper was a woman. - I noticed.
KGB的神射手也有女的
Some of the best KGB shots are women.
- 你有没有… - 我不想谈
- Did you... - I'd rather not talk about it.
好的 当然
No, of course not.
他们在找我
They are looking for me.
若他们封锁边境 我怎么出去?
If they close the border, how will I get out?
基奥治 别担心 我们有通往西方的输油管
Don't you worrv about that, Georgi. we have a pipeline to the west.
(跨西伯利亚输油管)
我是罗西卡
Rosika Miklos.
这是我们的人
Our man here.
好高兴再度跟你合作 邦德先生
Good to work with you again, Mr. Bond. Come.
保持安静
Keep quiet.
- 快点 把他放进小猪里 - 什么小猪?
- We must hurry. Get him in the pig. - Pig? what is pig?
清洗输油管的塞子
Scouring plug to clean out the pipeline.
但这是为了运送人而设计的
This one's been designed to carrv a man.
输油管? 你是说我们的输油管吗?
Pipeline? You mean our pipeline?
苏维埃的伟大发明 运送天然气到西欧
Great Soviet achievement. Piping natural gas into western Europe.
但不是运送我
But not me!
别担心 不过是小意思
Don't worrv. It's a piece of cake.
别再说了
Never mind cake.
若你在一百度以前开动栓塞 他就会变成罗宋汤
If you open valye before 100, he will be borscht.
小猪 罗宋汤 一定有别的方法吧
Pigs, borscht, cake. There must be another way.
进去吧
Get in.
戴上面具 正常的呼吸
Put on the mask and breathe normally.
- 别再说了 - 基奥治 放松一点
- Enough talk. - Relax, Georgi.
我们的工程师花了几个月 研究这东西
Our engineers spent months perfecting this.
- 这东西你们用过多少次?  - 这是第一次
- How many times have you done this? - You're the first.
记住 到了一百度 开动这个 别提早了
Remember,when this says 100, turn this. Not before.
- 你上哪里去?  - 去收拾这里的主管
- Where are you going? - To take care of the supervisor.
小猪弹出去的时候 他的控制台会好像圣诞树般闪亮
When pig goes, his control panel will light up like Christmas tree.
你以为我是什么人?
''What kind of girl do you think I am?''
上将 欢迎来到奥地利
Welcome to Austria, General.
来吧
Come on.
往上走
Up you go.
来吧! 快点!
Come on. Hurry up! Come on!
我们接到他了
We've got him.
麻烦你 关上它
Excuse me. Shut it.
谢谢
Thank you.
开心点 桑德斯
Cheer up, Saunders.
任务成功了 都归功于你
The operation's a success and officially still yours.
我不会这样就算了 007
I have no intention of leaving it at that, 007.
我会告诉M你故意打不中她
I'm telling M that you deliberately missed.
你的任务是杀掉狙击手
Your orders were to kill that sniper.
别瞎说 我只杀专业的杀手
Stuff my orders. I only kill professionals.
那个女孩连枪头跟枪尾也分不清
That girl didn't know one end of a rifle from the other.
你要告诉M 随便你 若他开除我 我会谢谢他
Tell M what you want. If he fires me, I'll thank him for it.
不管她是谁 我已经把她吓个半死
Whoever she was, I must've scared the living davlights out of her.
俄罗斯上将投诚了!
Russian general defects!
俄国名将投诚了!
Famous Russian general defects.
尤李亚考夫 三人确定已经死亡 两人可能已经死亡
Ula Yokhfov. Confirmed kills: three. Probable kills: two.
行刺方式 用手或以大腿扼死敌人
Assassination methods: strangulation with hands or thighs.
詹姆斯 她正是你喜欢的类型
Why,James, she's just your tvpe.
你错了 钱班霓 你才是
Wrong again, Monevpennv. You are.
我会把这个跟其他秘密资料 一起存档
I'll file that with the other secret information here.
专长是扮成小孩
Specialist: child impersonations.
行刺方式是用藏有炸弹的玩具熊
Assassination method: explosive teddv bears.
这就是所有KGB女杀手的资料
Now,that's all the KGB female assassins.
我们可以试用 驻守苏维埃外的雇佣兵
You know,we could trv freelancers stationed outside the Soviet bloc.
时间不够 M在布莱登安全房等你
It'll have to wait. M wants you out at the Blavden safe house.
好的
Right.
反正留在这儿也没意思
Looks like it's a dead end here anyway.
很好
Ah, good!
我们为美国人研制了一些东西
Something we're making for the Americans.
叫做贫民区轰击炮
It's called a ghetto blaster.
快点走吧
You'd better hurry.
M想你中途在哈罗德斯百货公司 拿点东西
M wants you to stop at Harrods on your way and pick up a parcel.
钱班霓 帮我一个忙
Monevpennv, be a dear.
叫记录部去察看捷克的出版商 或新问部
Ask Records to monitor Czech publication and news services...
布拉迪斯拉发的公立音乐学院 有没有女大提琴手
...for any mention of a woman cellist at the conservatoire in Bratislava.
原来你也喜欢音乐
I didn't know you were such a music lover,James.
什么时候来我家听一听
Any time you want to drop by and listen to...
我的巴里曼尼洛系列
...my Barry Manilow collection....
对不起 借一下
Sorry, sir. Excuse me.
死北方佬
Bloodv Yanks.
你早
Good morning, sir.
控制中心 007正在途中
Control here. 007's on his way.
你早
Good morning.
对不起 邦德先生 请把枪留下
Sorry, Mr. Bond. You'll have to leave the metal.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
- 早 有什么可以效劳?  - 不 我自己去就行
- Good morning. May I help you? - No,thanks. I'll manage.
他们在客厅等你
They're expecting you in the drawing room.
进来
Come.
詹姆斯
James.
我会记得你为我所做的
James, I will never forget what you did for me.
谢谢…这是什么?
Thank you so... what's this?
来自哈罗德斯的好东西
From Harrods. A godsend.
- 这里的食物很糟 - 鹅肝酱却不错
- The food here is horrible. - The foie gras is excellent.
俄罗斯人有个说法 讲心讲胃 才是好同志
As Russians say, hearts and stomachs good comrades make.
这是鱼子酱?  这是我们农家的食物
What's this? Caviar? That's peasant food for us.
但给香槟下酒也不错
But with champagne, it's okay.
勃林加酒是最好的!
Bollinger R.D. The best!
单子上的牌子不够好
The brand on the list was questionable...
所以我另选别的
...so I chose something else.
非常好 邦德先生
Superb, Mr. Bond! Superb.
我们继续简报好吗?
May I suggest we resume the debriefing?
好 继续吧 我准备好了
Absolutely. Go ahead. I'm all yours.
- 平时那个送牛奶的人呢?  - 什么?
- Where's the usual milkman? - What'd you say?
平时那个送牛奶的人呢?
Where's the usual man?
感冒了
Flu.
小心点
Hey, mate,watch it.
厨房入口在后面
Kitchen entrance. Round the back.
我为了利昂尼普谢金上将 才变节的
General Leonid Pushkin is why I defect!
你的KGB上级?
Your KGB superior?
当高戈去外国执行任务时的代里人
Gogol's replacement when he went to their foreign service.
我们曾经是好兄弟 现在他整个人都变了
Once we were like brothers, but now he's a different man.
他被权力冲昏了头脑 好像斯达林一样疯了
Power has gone to his head. He's sick, like Stalin.
他不喜欢我们的新政策
He hates our new policv of detente.
现在有一个
I have here...
普谢金的秘密命令
...secret directive from Pushkin.
诛杀特务行动
Smiert Spionom.
意思是杀死间谍 部长
''Death to spies,'' minister.
是一个行刺计划
For an assassination program with list of targets...
目标是英美的特务
...British and American agents.
计划开始了   就会展开连厂仇杀
When this starts,you will retaliate. Murder will follow murder.
苏维埃和西方的情报机关 会互相残杀
Soviet and western intelligence could destrov each other.
天啊 这会引起核战
God forbid,this might lead to nuclear war!
除非可以…
Unless Pushkin can be....
该怎么说?
How do you say?
把普谢金杀了
Put away.
他现在在哪里? 莫斯科?
Where is Pushkin now? In Moscow?
是的 但三天之内他会到丹吉尔
Da, but in three davs, he will leave for Tangier.
表面原因是参加北非贸易会议
Cover: North African Trade Convention.
真正原因是
Real reason:
执行新任务
New directive.
部长 根据科斯克夫先生刚才说的
Minister, in view of the importance of what Mr. Koskov has just told us...
我们应该休会 到伦敦联络高层
...we should adjourn to London and consult with higher authoritv.
- 当然 科斯克夫先生再见 - 再见
- By all means. Good dav, Mr. Koskov. - Good dav, sir.
给你吃 乖乖
There you go. There's a good lad.
- 你早 - 请放在这里好吗?
- Good morning. - Put it down there,would you?
谢谢
Thanks.
绿四队呼叫基地
Green 4 to base.
绿四队…
Green 4, Green 4.
这是保安控制中心 你在哪里?
This is Security Control. Whereare you?
绿四队 这是控制中心 请回答
Green 4, this is Security. Comein,please.
绿四队 你听见吗?
Green 4, do you read me?
绿四队呼叫基地 主大楼泄漏了危险气体
Green 4 to base. we have dangerous gas leaks in main building.
马上撤离 找紧急医疗队求助
Evacuateimmediately. Sendfor emergency medical services.
绿四队 收到你的讯息了
Green 4, l readand understand you.
控制中心通知各单位 开始实施十号紧急措施
Controltoall stations. Code 10. lnitiate emergency drill.
马上撤离主大楼
Evacuate the main building.
紧急状态…
Emergency. Emergency.
各单位马上撤离主大楼
All personnel evacuate the main building.
绿四队呼叫基地
Green 4 to base.
发生了气体爆炸 别走近主大楼
We've had a gas explosion. Keep clear of the main building.
是KGB
KGB!
大家往后退
Keep back, everybody!
- 起来 - 不要杀我
- Get up. - Don't kill me.
- 走吧 - 不要杀我!
- Come on. - Don't kill me!
走
Move.
走!
Move!
不要走近主大楼
Keep clear of the main building.
- 用来载谁?  - 你 同志
- Who's that for? - You, comrade.
帮他 否则我杀了你们俩
Help him or I kill you both.
走!
Move!
快点!
Hurry!
两人死亡 两人受伤送院
Two dead,two in a hospital...
若科斯克夫还没有死的话 他该回到莫斯科了
...and Koskov probably back in Moscow, if not dead.
我们成了整个特务界的笑柄
We're the laughingstock of the intelligence communitv.
这是我们多年来最严重的打击 被KGB成功的在他变节后…
Our first major coup in vears snatched from right under our noses...
几小时之内又将他劫回
...by the KGB only hours after he defected.
- 找不到他?  - 找不到
- No trace of him? - Nothing.
还有普谢金的计划
Then there's this Pushkin matter.
我得走了
Well, I must be off.
下午跟首相开会
Meeting with the PM this afternoon.
我们得制止诛杀特杀行动
We have to nip Smiert Spionom in the bud.
普谢金两天之内该到达丹吉尔
Pushkin should be in Tangier in two davs' time.
有人下了暗杀令要杀掉他
A termination warrant has been issued for him.
这个诛杀特务的命令似乎太牵强
This plot to kill agents sounds rather far-fetched, sir.
- 我认识普谢金上将 - 难道我不认识他?
- I know General Pushkin. - And you think I don't?
我跟他交过几次手
I've dealt with him on several occasions.
往后几年我们都有碰头
Our paths have crossed over the vears.
他这人强硬又足智多谋 不像是个疯子
He's tough and resourceful, but I can't believe he's a psvchotic.
我也不相信 但现在不得不相信
Neither did I, until today.
这东西由直布罗陀送来 在004身旁发现的
This arrived from Gibraltar. It was found near 004's body.
诛杀特务行动
Your name was on Pushkin's list too, 007.
有几件事情我得先弄清楚
There are a few things I'd like to check out first.
比如说 那个狙击手
That sniper,for instance.
对 我也看过桑德斯的报告
Yes, I've read Saunders' report.
你为了不射杀那漂亮的女孩 而危及整个任务
You jeopardized the entire mission to avoid shooting a beautiful girl.
不对 我作了一个即时的决定
Not exactly, sir. I had to make a split-second decision.
是出于本能的
It was instinct.
我会从香港召回008 由他接手
I'll recall 008 from Hong Kong. He can do it.
他根本不认识普谢金
He doesn't know Pushkin.
他服从命令 而不是按本能行事
He follows orders, not instincts.
- 你可以放两星期假 - 不行
- You can take a fortnight's leave. - No.
长官
Sir.
如果一定要这样
If it has to be done...
我宁愿自己来
...I'd rather do it.
慢慢放下来 轻一点 好了
Bring it down slowly. Gently, now.
- Q 你早 - 007 你早
- Morning, Q. - Morning, 007.
小心你的头
Mind your head.
我有些东西给你
I've got something for you.
这个是刚研制的
We're just winterizing this.
007 留心听着
Now, pay attention, 007.
这是万能钥匙
Kev-ring finder.
讲解一下
Surprise me.
按这个按钮就变武器 就这样子 见到吗?
You arm it by pressing that button there. Like that, see?
好 戴上这个
Right. Now wear that.
好了 吹出《大不列颠万岁》第一节
Right. Now,whistle the first bars of ''Rule Britannia.''
迷晕气体
Stun gas.
有效范围只有五尺
Effective range: oh, about five feet.
迷昏一个正常人 只需要
Disorientates any normal person for about...
三十秒
...30 seconds.
这行业里没几个正常人的 Q
Don't find too many normal people in this business, Q.
我怎么炸毁那房间?  吹"天佑女王"?
How do I blow up the room? whistle ''God save the Queen''?
我们在万能钥匙里
We've packed the finder...
装设了高浓度的塑胶炸药
...with a highly concentrated plastic explosive...
足以炸开任何保险箱的门
...sufficient to remove the door of any safe.
由磁力控制 可以自订个人启动讯号
It's magnetic. The actuating signal is personalized.
- 我的讯号是什么?  - 是最适合你的
- What's my code? - Oh, most appropriate.
- 狼叫声 - 你是说…
- A wolf whistle. - You mean....
停!
Stop!
这些钥匙对你很有用
You mav find the kevs useful.
它可开启世界上百分之九十的锁
They open 90% of the world's locks.
好了 请坐 好好休息
All right. Sit down and make yourself comfortable.
干得好 钱班霓 就是她
Well done. That's her.
记录部刚送来这份翻译
Records just sent over this translation.
卡拉米劳维 出色的大提琴手 曾获奖学金
''Kara Milovy,talented scholarship cellist...
上星期演奏会休息时 手臂意外受伤
...whose arm was injured in an accident during intermission last week...
星期四将会回到学院
...will be back at the academy on Thursdav...
演奏波洛丁的《弦乐四重奏D调第二号乐曲》
playing Borodin's "String Quartet No. 2 in D".
那是明天了
That's tomorrow.
钱班霓 请预备经过布拉迪斯拉发 到丹吉尔的旅游证件
Monevpennv, I'll need travel documents for Tangier via Bratislava.
这是我们的秘密
And keep this between ourselyes.
她一定很出色
That girl must be very talented.
相信我 我只因为工作关系才对她有兴趣
Believe me, my interest in her is purely professional.
我要开阿士顿马丁
Just taking the Aston Martin out for a quick spin, Q.
小心点 007 我刚喷上油漆呢
Be careful, 007. It's just had a new coat of paint!
(卡拉米劳维 布拉迪斯拉发)
我把枪丢到河里去
I dropped the gun in the river.
KGB把这里弄得一团糟
KGB made quite a mess.
你是英国人 你是谁?
You're English. who are you?
我昨天在公立音乐学院 听你的演奏
I heard you play at the conservatoire vesterdav.
很出色
It was exquisite.
我看见在电车发生的事 他们带你到哪里去了?
I saw what happened on the tram. where did they take you?
KGB总部?
KGB headquarters?
他们今早放我走了
They released me this morning.
看看对街
Take a look across the street.
他们让你走 然后就可以跟踪你
They let you go so they could follow you.
我不明白 你干嘛帮我?
I don't understand. why are you trving to help me?
普谢金想怎么样?
What did Pushkin want?
他有问你 基奥治科斯克夫的情况吗?
Did he ask you about Georgi Koskov?
他想知道他在哪里
He wanted to know where he was.
- 你告诉了他?  - 没有
- Did you tell him? - No.
基奥治真聪明 懂得用空弹
It was clever of Georgi, using blanks.
让英方以为他真的投诚
Made the British believe his defection was real.
你怎么知道?
How do you know that?
他跟我说的
He told me.
- 你见过他?  - 两天前 他现在很好
- You saw him? - Two davs ago. He's safe and sound.
你是他朋友?
You're a friend of his?
我们俩一起经历过许多患难
We've been through quite a lot together.
基奥治 他果然守信找人来找我了
Dear Georgi. He kept his promise to send for me.
我们要去哪里? 伦敦?
Where are we going? To London?
不 英方认为 他暂时到别的地方会比较安全
Not vet. The British think he'll be safer if he moves around for a while.
我们也许可以在维也纳和他会合
We might catch up with him in Vienna.
我们得在他们 再抓到你以前
We must leave immediately...
马上离开这里
...before they pick you up again.
- 怎么走呢?  - 我们自有办法
- But how? - We'll manage.
收拾行李 带些保温的衣服
Get packed. Bring some warm clothes.
我们好像过关了
It looks like we got away with it.
我的大提琴 我留在音乐学院了
My cello! It's at the conservatoire.
- 在维也纳给你再买一个 - 不 我们要回去拿
- I'll get you another in Vienna. - No,we must go back for it.
在他们会发现怎么回事之前 我们只有十分种
We have about 10 minutes before they discover what's happened.
- 我一定要取回我的大提琴 - 不行
- I must get my cello. - No way!
快点进来
Come on. Get in.
你怎么不学小提琴?
Why didn't you learn the violin?
你截听了警察频道
You picked up the police band.
一定是大气电波反常
It must be an atmospheric anomaly.
他们在找一辆外国的车 和一对男女
They're looking for a foreign car, a man and a woman.
还带着一个大提琴
And a cello.
看来给发现了
Looks like they just found us.
停在一旁吧
Pull over to the side and stop!
怎么了?
What happened?
车子受侵蚀了
Salt corrosion.
他们设了路障
They're setting up roadblocks.
那是什么?
What is this?
我还加装了几个东西
I've had a few extras installed.
好神奇 现代的安全玻璃真厉害
Amazing,this modern safetv glass.
小心
Look out!
看看这条路通往哪里
See where this leads to.
只能够通往一个大湖
This road only leads to the lake.
我们得走了
Time to leave.
当心自己
Brace yourself.
我们成功了
We almost made it.
(自我毁灭)
快来吧 走了!
Come on, quick! Go!
幸好我坚持要你回去拿大提琴
Glad I insisted you brought that cello.
对不起
Sorry.
快到了
Not far now.
到了 拿起给他们看
Here. waye this.
快躺下
Duck!
- 我们没有东西报关! - 只有一个大提琴!
- We've nothing to declare! - Just the cello!
檀吉尔
TANGIERS
请你在这里等
If you wait here, sir...
我去找主管
...I'll find the chief.
普谢金上将
General Pushkin.
幸会 我是布拉德惠特克
It's a pleasure. I'm Brad whitaker.
没想过在丹吉尔会见到你 科斯克夫跟你一起?
Didn't expect to see you in Tangier. General Koskov with you?
战争 人类的主要工作就是战争
War. War's always been man's main occupation.
只有傻挂才说最伟大的发明是 文字或是轮子
Fools say his greatest accomplishments were the wheel or the alphabet.
我说是火药和撞锤才对
I say it's a battering ram and gunpowder.
你喜欢我这忠烈祠吗?
How do you like my pantheon of great commanders?
屠夫
Butchers.
是外科医生
Surgeons.
他们割掉社会的腐肉
They cut away societv's dead flesh.
给你看些东西 稍息 军士
Let me show you something. At ease, sergeant.
这边走
This way, sir.
我的爱好是研究 世界历史战争的策略和战术
My hobby. The strategv and tactics of the world's historic battles.
1985年 阿富汉的西北前线
Afghanistan, the Northwest Frontier, 1895.
首次试验第一把自动机关枪
The initial trial of the first automatic machine gun:
点303马克沁口径
.303 caliber Maxim.
皇家来福枪 曾扫除庞大的精锐部队
The king's roval rifles. They wiped out a vastly superior force.
把英国人多困在阿富汉二十五年
Kept the British in Afghanistan for another 25 vears.
现在俄国人需要的是 现代化的马克沁武器
What you Russians need nowadavs is the equivalent of a modern Maxim.
第三代星光观察仪器
Third-generation starlight scopes.
是雷射瞄准短筒机关枪
A laser-sighting short-barreled machine pistol.
步兵部队迷你导弹 射程五公里
Infantrv mini-missiles. Range: five kilometers.
很棒 按一下就行了
And smart. Just fire and forget.
它无坚不摧
It penetrates all existing armor.
这就是你订货的样本
Yes, sir, samples of everything ordered.
订单已经取消
The order is canceled.
四十八小时内 你得退回五千万元订金
You'll return our deposit of $50 million within the next 48 hours.
你不是认真的 将军
You can't be serious, general.
你知道得到这些武器有多困难?
Do you know how hard it is to obtain this equipment?
这是美国与欧洲最新的产品
I mean,this is the latest U.S. and European stuff.
我又借又赊才弄到的
I made commitments, letters of credit, special payoffs.
我们的钱在你的瑞士银行户口 已经八个星期
We know that you've had our monev in your Swiss account for 8 weeks...
...但是你从没付过任何款项
...and that you have made no payments of any kind.
但现在取消订单已经太迟了
But I can't cancel orders at this late date.
作为一个老兵 要守诺言...
As one old soldier to another, you have my word we will deliver...
别对我摆出军人的样子
Spare me your militarv pretensions.
你在哪个军队服役?
What army did you serve in?
你因诈骗而被西点赶出来
You were expelled from west Point for cheating.
然后在比利时属刚果 当短期的雇佣兵
Then a short stint as a mercenarv in the Belgian Congo.
后来你在支持你做军火卖买
Later you worked with various criminal organizations...
...的不同的犯罪集团混
...that financed your first arms deals.
那是我的对手发放的谣言
Lies spread by my competitors.
你好像忘了很多 我曾经过科斯克夫...
You seem to forget your many so-called wars of liberation...
...提供武器给你进行 你所谓的解放战争
...that I have supplied through General Koskov.
那是我的商业信誉
Those are my business credentials.
你两天之内给我钱...
The monev in two davs...
...否则你永远别想干这行
...or you will find yourself out of business permanently.
基奥治也是
Georgi Koskov as well.
我不知道你们俩在搞什么...
I don't know what you two are scheming...
...但是够了 明白了没有?
...but it is over. Is that understood?
小心
Careful.
计程车!
Taxi!
就像基奥治所说 维也纳好美
Vienna's beautiful, just like Georgi said.
你很关心他 是吗?
You care for him a great deal, don't you?
我欠他的太多了
I owe him everything.
我在公立音乐学院的奖学金 我的斯特拉提琴
My scholarship at the conservatoire, my Strad.
你的大提琴是斯特拉的?
Your cello's a Stradivarius?
很有名的 叫做玫瑰夫人
A famous one. The Ladv Rose.
- 基奥治在纽约买的 - 不错的礼物
- Georgi got it in New York. - Quite a present.
也许有天我会在卡内基演奏厅
Maybe somedav I'll play there at Carnegie Hall.
- 基奥治认为我可以的 - 他说得对
- Georgi believes I can do it. - I'm sure he's right.
- 我们现在去找他? - 好的
- We go to him now? - Yeah.
除非他已走了
Unless he had to move on.
若他真的走了 他定会留个讯息
If he did, I'm sure he left a message.
谢谢
Danke.
小心
Careful.
午安 邦德先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Bond.
你住平时那间套房吗?
You will need your usual suite?
不是 汉斯 要两个相连的套房
Not tonight, Hans. Something with a second bedroom.
要送伏特加马丁尼来吗?
Shall I have the vodka martinis sent up?
要摇的 不要搅的
Shaken, not stirred.
知道了
Of course.
国际出口部
Universal Exports.
我是邦德 我要两张歌剧门票 左边厢房的
Bond here. I need two tickets for the opera left at the box office.
喜欢吗?
Do you like it?
- 给公主的还是政委夫人的?  - 买吧
- For princess or wife of commissar? - Let's buv it.
别开玩笑 谁付钱呢?
Don't joke. who will pay?
当然是基奥治
Georgi, of course.
别这样
Please. Stop it, please.
长官找你
The chief wants you.
我们得去报告
We have to report.
很好 稍息 军士
Verv good. At ease, sergeant.
普谢金想要回钱
Pushkin wants the monev back.
别担心
Don't worrv.
我们说服了英方 普谢金是个危险人物
We've convinced the British that Pushkin is a danger.
他们会派最好的特务詹姆斯邦德 去铲除他
They will send their best man, James Bond,to eliminate him.
我不相信 尼高斯也做得到吧
Well, I'm not convinced. Necros can do it.
我曾经跟俄罗斯人合作 他们知道我的底细
I've worked with the Russians. They know my appearance and methods.
那会危害跟我有关的革命同志
It mav jeopardize my comrades working for revolution who depend on me.
他们依赖我 除了我还有谁可以提供军备呢?
And they depend upon me. where else will they find a supply of arms?
我们本来的计划很好
Our basic plan is sound.
普谢金…该怎么说呢? 玩完了
Pushkin is.... How you say? Historv.
还不是 你们的邦德还没动他呢
Not vet. Your James Bond hasn't laid a finger on him.
英国人天生多疑
The British are naturally cautious.
再刺激一下他们
An additional inducement will ensure this.
比如说 若另一个特务被杀了?
For instance, if another agent were eliminated?
干吧 若普谢金有命参加会议 就杀了他!
Do it. But if Pushkin is still alive during the conference, kill him!
- 我梦寐以求的事情 - 也许有一天你会在这里表演
- All my life, I've dreamed of this. - Maybe you'll play here one dav.
那太遥不可及
It's too much to hope for.
我要离开一会儿
Excuse me for a few moments.
- 这不就是...  - 大提琴的女孩
- Isn't that the... - The cello girl.
是KGB狙击手 干嘛带她到这里?
The KGB sniper. why bring her here?
她不是KGB狙击手 她是科斯克夫的女朋友
She's not a KGB sniper. She's Koskov's girlfriend.
她负责向他发空弹 让他的逃亡看来是真的
She was supposed to shoot blanks at him to make his defection look real to us.
他伪装逃亡?  听说KGB把他抓回去了
Koskov's defection phonv? I heard the KGB snatched him back.
这只是我们以为的
That's what we were supposed to think.
这是严重的控罪 你现在在做什么?
These are serious accusations, Bond. What are you up to?
我假装是科斯克夫的朋友 看看从她身上可以打听到什么
I'm posing as Koskov's friend just to see what leads I can get from her.
你知道他在纽约给她买了 叫玫瑰夫人的大提琴
You know he bought her a cello in New York, called The Ladv Rose.
大提琴有名字吗?
A cello with a name?
是斯拉特系列的 全部都有名字
It's a Stradivarius. They all have names.
你去调查科斯克夫 从哪里来这么多的钱?
Now,where would Koskov get that kind of monev? Check it out.
还有我今晚要给她预备身分文件
And I'll need papers for her tonight.
明天我就要把她送离这国家
I have to get her out of the countrv by tomorrow.
这里 今天下午照的
Here. Took these this afternoon.
看 这不合规矩
Look,this is highly irregular.
我起码要一天才能得到伦敦批准
I won't be able to get the okay from London for a dav at least.
我不能再等了   桑德斯
It can't wait, Saunders.
这女的是我们找到 科斯克夫的唯一希望
That girl's our only chance of getting Koskov back.
很好 除了退休金以外 我没什么损失
Verv well. I've got nothing to lose but my pension.
今晚在柏拉达咖啡店等我 在摩天轮附近
Meet me at the Prater Cafe, near the Ferris wheel, at midnight.
- 够了 - 这个
- No more. - This one.
带我上摩天轮去
Take me on the wheel.
你可以看得清楚一点
You'll be able to see better.
- 要汽球吗?  - 不
- Balloon,mein Herr? - Nein.
是现实还是梦境?
Is it real or just a dream?
怎么了? 干嘛停下来了?
What's wrong? why did we stop?
我安排的
I arranged it.
我们可以整个晚上都留在这里
We could be here all night.
不 不可能的
Don't. It's impossible.
只认识你两天 我都在想 我们怎样可以在一起
Knowing you only 2 davs, and all I can think of is how we would be together.
别想了 就让它发生吧
Don't think. Just let it happen.
想再玩一次吗?
Do you want another ride?
我等一下就回来
I'll be back in a minute.
可能有人给我留讯息
There mav be a message for me.
那是他最近在纽约的拍卖会买的
It was bought recently at auction in New York.
124号 玫瑰夫人
''Lot 124. The Ladv Rose.
1724年克雷莫纳 斯特拉大提琴
A cello by Stradivarius of Cremona, 1724.''
以十五万元...
Sold for $150,000...
...卖给布拉德惠特克
...to Brad whitaker.
惠特克? 那军火商?
Whitaker? The arms dealer?
一样的
The same.
是科斯克夫和惠特克
Koskov and whitaker.
惠特克现在哪里?
Where's whitaker now?
在丹吉尔他家
At his place in Tangier.
做得好
Well done.
祝你好运
Good luck.
桑德斯
Saunders.
谢谢你
Thanks.
你去哪里?
Where are you going?
怎么了?
What's the matter?
有基奥治的消息?
Hear from Georgi?
是的
Yes.
我有消息
I got the message.
他跟惠特克在丹吉尔
He's with whitaker in Tangier.
布拉德惠特克? 那美国人?
Brad whitaker? The American?
- 你认识他 - 他是个艺术家
- You know him. - He's a patron of the arts.
基奥治说他会帮我的
Georgi said he'd help me.
我们多快可以启程?
How soon do we have to go?
立该
Immediately.
我答应基奥治尽快送你回去
I promised Georgi I'd get you back as soon as I could.
不能多留几天吗?
Can't we stav here a few davs?
不 明天早上就走
No. we leave first thing in the morning.
怎么了?
Is anything wrong?
邦德
Bond.
别乱动 上将
Don't make any sudden moves, general.
走向桌子
Go to the table.
没事的
It's all right.
坐下来
Sit down.
我想你不是来联谊的 007
I take it that this is not a social call, 007.
对 你该带百合花
Correct. You should have brought lilies.
为什么?
May I ask why?
诛杀特务行动
Smiert Spionom.
诛杀特务行动...
Smiert Spionom...
...那是斯达林时代的贝利亚行动
...was a Beria operation in Stalin's time.
二十年前已经废除
It was deactivated 20 vears ago.
我们死了两个特务
Two of our agents are dead.
节哀顺变 我们跟这件事无关
My condolences. we had nothing to do with it.
科斯克夫在哪里?
Where's Koskov?
他两星期前失踪前
He disappeared two weeks ago.
- 本来我要捉他 - 为什么?
- I was about to have him arrested. - Why?
- 他浪费国家经费 - 惠特克有参与吗?
- For misusing state funds. - Involying whitaker?
这是机密问题 不能跟你讨论
That is a securitv matter and cannot be discussed.
那真笨!
That was damn stupid!
躲在浴室把门锁上
Get in the bathroom and lock the door.
不要动
Stav where you are.
跪下来
Get down on your knees.
把手放在脑后
Put your hands behind your back.
你是专业的 不会在没有原因下杀人
You are professional. You do not kill without reason.
我们两个人死了 科斯克夫说是你干的
Two of our men are dead. Koskov's named you.
- 我干嘛达抗命令?  - 我跟你一样不知情
- Now,why should I disobev my orders? - I am in the dark as much as you are.
这是信任问题
It is a question of trust.
你相信谁呢? 科斯克夫还是我?
Who do you believe? Koskov or me?
若我相信科斯克夫 就不会在这里跟你说话
If I trusted Koskov, we wouldn't be talking.
但只要你还活着
But as long as you're alive...
我们不知道他会怎么样
...we'll never know what he's up to.
那我一定要死
Then I must die.
各位来宾
Ladies and gentlemen...
我很荣幸介绍俄罗斯代表主席
...it is indeed my honor to introduce the head of the Russian delegation...
利昂尼普谢金同志
...Comrade Leonid Pushkin.
各位代表
Honored delegates...
我代表苏维埃共和国的同志
...I bring you profound fraternal greetings...
向你们致以友好的问候
...from your comrades in Soviet Union.
到上面!
Up there!
不要! …
No! No!
封锁这大楼! 一个人都不能离去!
Seal the building! Let no one out!
不要! 利昂尼!
No! Leonid!
你想去玩吗?
You looking for a partv?
好像是个不错的提议
Seems like a good idea.
抱歉要你受那么多苦
I'm sorry to put you through that, my dear.
这是我第一次 因为詹姆斯邦德是个好射手
That is the first time I've ever been grateful...
而感到庆幸
...that James Bond is a good shot.
停下来吧 下次再玩吧
Pull over here. we can have a partv some other time.
给你的小礼物
Little present for you.
不够吗?
Not enough?
全部拿去
Take it all.
好好的享受吧
Just sit back and enjov the ride.
到下面去
Down below.
你究竟想搞什么鬼 007?
What the hell are you trving to do, 007?
引发第三次世界大战吗?
Start world war III?
菲利斯利达 好了 中央情报局在这干嘛?
Felix Leiter. Now, what's the CIA doing here?
干得好
Nice work, girls.
不会觉得不开心?
No hard feelings?
只要派对继续就行了
Not if the party's still on.
这故事很长 但最后普谢金奇迹地康复
It's a long story, but in the end, Pushkin makes a miraculous recovery.
这只是虚张声势?
You mean this is a put-up job?
这是怎么回事?
What's all this?
自从几天前他跟惠特克见面 我们就开始监视普谢金
We've been watching Pushkin since he met a couple of davs ago with whitaker.
- 和俄罗斯的非法军火买卖?  - 你问倒我了
- Illegal arms deal with the Russians? - Well,you've got me.
惠特克 带了几个高科技东西样本
Whitaker's put together a few samples of high-tech stuff...
...但现在还没做成大买卖
...but he's placed no big orders vet.
我们似乎以不同的方向 干同一件事
Looks like we've been working on the same case from opposite ends.
让我们好好谈谈
Let's talk shop.
很好
Well done.
恭喜你 我们在收音机听到了
Congratulations. we heard it over the radio.
我没杀他 是邦德干的
I didn't kill him. Bond did.
我已经告诉你英国人相信我!
I told you the British believed me!
我说过了!
I told you! I told you!
现在可以走了 我会通知阿姆斯特丹把钻石运来
Now we can move. I'll signal Amsterdam to ship the diamonds.
先生?
Sir?
你好 是
Hello. Yes.
谁?
Who?
给你的
It's for you.
你好
Hello.
你去哪里了 詹姆斯?
Where have you been,James?
你去了那么久 我好担心
You were gone so long, I was worried.
被人想念的感觉很好
Well, it's always nice to be missed.
还是找不到基奥治
Still no sign of Georgi.
- 不 请继续 - 不
- No, please. Go on playing. - No.
喝点东西吧
Let's have a drink.
你记得
You remembered.
为了我们
To us.
干杯
Nazdravi.
那些酒调得好吗?
Did I get it right?
非常好
Perfect.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
卡拉 是时候把真相告诉你
Kara, it's time I told you the truth.
我不是基奥治的朋友 我是寻找他的英国特务
I'm not a friend of Georgi's. I'm a British agent looking for him.
他背叛了我们
He's betraved us all, Kara.
俄罗斯人 英国人...
The Russians,the British...
...甚至是你
...even you.
他告诉我们狙击手要杀他
He told us a sniper might try to kill him.
然后他令你成为狙击手
Then he set you up as the sniper, Kara.
他要你死因为你知道得太多
He wants you dead. You knew too much.
骗子! 你假装爱我
Liar! You pretended to love me.
我打电话找惠特克 基奥治在他那里
I telephoned whitaker. Georgi was there.
他把真相告诉我
He told me the truth.
你这KGB特务利用我来找他 然后杀死他!
You're a KGB agent using me to find him and kill him!
不 不是...
No,that's not...
不是真的 我...
That's not true. I...
亲爱的卡拉
Kara, my darling.
你真是完美
You were absolutely perfect.
快点
Hurry.
先生 请下车
Sortez, s'il yous plait.
移植用的人类器官
Merci, monsieur.
打开它
Open it, please.
小心点 必须绝对卫生无菌
Careful. It must be kept absolutely sterile.
走吧
Go.
我一直都被骗了
I've been such a fool.
我们都是
We both have.
把盖子打开
Open the lid.
我的天
Oh, my God.
这不是人的器官 这是动物的心脏
That's not human. It's an animal's heart.
钻石藏在冰里面
Diamonds hidden in the ice.
- 我怎样可以帮你?  - 找我的钥匙圈
- How can I help you? - I need my kev ring.
小心
Look out.
给客人一杯黑咖啡
Black coffee for our guest.
她真聪明
She has so many talents.
我一直在想
I'm curious.
你干嘛不杀我?
Why didn't you kill me?
我不是野蛮人
I'm not a barbarian,James.
我带你去苏维埃有关当局...
I'm taking you to the proper Soviet authorities...
...说你杀了普谢金上将
...for the killing of General Pushkin.
你真厉害 你让我为你杀了普谢金...
You're a wonder, Georgi. You get me to kill Pushkin for you...
...然后把我交给俄罗斯
...then you turn me in to the Russians for his murder.
你想要求什么?
What are you going to ask for?
豁免权?
Immunity?
移民西方和享受新生活?
Permission to emigrate and enjoy the amenities of the west?
他们不会原谅你的变节吧?
You don't honestly think they'll condone your defection, do you?
什么变节?
What defection?
我为普谢金进行秘密任务...
I have been on a secret mission for General Pushkin...
...就是给英方情报机关提供假情报
...to disinform British Intelligence.
抱歉 詹姆斯
I'm sorry,James.
我真的很喜欢你...
For you I have great affection...
...但我们有个古老说法:
...but we have an old saying:
"完成任务不可以感情用事"
''Duty has no sweethearts.''
我们也有个老说法 基奥治
We have an old saying too, Georgi.
"你真是混蛋"
''You're full of it.''
来吧 卡拉
Come, Kara.
- 卡拉?  - 是
- Kara? - Yes.
欢迎来到阿富汉
Welcome to Afghanistan.
费耶达上校 我的老朋友
Colonel Fevador, my old comrade in arms.
这是行刺普谢金上将的人
I have here General Pushkin's assassin...
英国特务007 詹姆斯邦德
...British agent 007,James Bond.
确定把他送到莫斯科
See he is sent to Moscow.
等一下 还有一个
One moment. There is one more.
把她也带走吧 她是个背叛者
Take her too. She's a defector.
我很同情你
I will be compassionate with you...
而且会试试安排你去 西伯利亚管弦乐团
...and trv to have you assigned to the Siberian Philharmonic Orchestra.
他们不错的 虽然他们的演奏技巧平庸
They're quite good, despite their bourgeois repertoire.
我在执行国家秘密任务
I am on a secret state mission.
我需要几队人和货车
I need a detachment of men and some trucks.
- 他们为什么而来呢?  - 谋杀
- What are these here for? - For murder.
谋杀!
Murder!
很久没有女囚犯了
I haven't had a woman prisoner for a long time.
来吧
Come.
鲁斯基 费耶达上校考虑了我的上诉没?
Rusky, has Colonel Fevador considered my appeal?
有的! 有好消息
Yes! Good news.
你明早不会被问吊 你会被枪射死
You won't be hung in the morning. You will be shot.
你弄错了! 我什么都没偷!
It's all a mistake! I stole nothing!
见到阿拉真神时对他说吧
You can tell Allah when you see him.
衣服脱光!
Strip!
大声说你要什么 这里有隔音的
Shout all you want. It's soundproof.
上校不喜欢听到有人尖叫
The colonel doesn't like to hear screaming.
我没叫你蹲下来
I didn't tell you to get down.
我没叫你站起来!
I did not tell you to get up!
现在 站起来
Now get up.
锁上门
Lock the door.
你真厉害 我们自由了!
You were fantastic. we're free!
我们在阿富汉中央的 俄罗斯空军基地
We're inside a Russian air base in the middle of Afghanistan.
试试小的那把钥匙
Trv the small key.
起码我们在一起
At least we're together.
很好 来
Terrific. Come on.
麻烦你?
Please?
来 跳吧!
Come on,jump!
- 怎么了?  - 我告诉他们你不是俄罗斯人
- What's going on? - I tell them you no Russian.
- 他们现在不会杀你 - 现在不会? 那晚点呢?
- They no kill you now. - Not now? How about later?
别担心 他们会为你的美色救你的
Don't worry. They'll saye you for the harem.
是穆加哈顿游击队的杰作
It's the work of the Mujahideen.
穆加哈顿游击队?
Mujahideen?
阿富汉的反抗者
The Afghan resistance.
希望没有请他吃晚饭
I hope he's not invited to dinner.
谢谢你们俩的帮忙
Thank you both for your help.
我叫甘兰沙
My name is Kamran Shah.
不要介意我的差劲演技 是我在牛津时学的
Please forgive the theatricals. It's a hangover from my Oxford davs.
相信你要换衣服
I'm sure you'd like to freshen up.
没事的 去吧
It's all right. Go ahead.
我得回空军基地去
I have to get back to the air base.
你疯了! 俄罗斯军队在找你
You're crazy! Russian army's looking for you.
你不帮我?
You won't help?
不
No.
那起码你带我去找 穆加哈顿游击队
Then at least put me in touch with the Mujahideen.
东部的副指挥官
Deputy commander of the Eastern District.
我在空军基地侦察时被捕了
I was caught reconnoitering the air base.
很幸运 但他们不知道我是谁
Thankfully for me, they didn't know who I was.
你是谁?
Now,who are you?
我为英国政府工作
I work for the British government.
我们揭发了俄罗斯科斯克夫上将
We've uncovered a plot by a Russian General Koskov...
...跟美国购买高科技武器的计划
...to purchase American high-tech weapons.
用来对付你和你的人
Arms that could be used against you.
这可跟我有关
That is important.
直接到凯巴关口找我们的指挥官
Go directly to our commander in the Khvber Pass.
那要好几天 我得在科斯克夫离开前赶到基地
That could take days. I have to get to the air base before Koskov leaves.
明天跟我们一起去 任务完成以后...
Look, come with us tomorrow and after our mission...
- 看看我可以做什么 - 那太迟了
- ...I'll see what I can do. - That'll be too late.
我要手枪和带路的人
I need a gun and some guides.
不可能 我们没有多余的人或马
Impossible. I cannot spare men or the horses.
是时候休息了
And now it is time to rest.
日出的时候出发
We leave at sunrise.
我好担心你
I was worried for you,James.
我们会怎样?
What's going to happen to us?
什么意思?
What does that mean?
是阿富汉语"漂亮"的意思
It means ''beautiful'' in Afghan.
我们在穆加哈顿游击队地盘
We're with the Mujahideen.
明天我们和他们走 执行些任务
We leave with them tomorrow on some kind of operation.
你则去凯巴关口
And you're going to the Khvber Pass.
你不跟我一起?
You're not coming with me?
不 我晚点才跟着去
No. I'll catch up with you later.
你不是要回去找基奥治吗?
You're going back for Georgi, aren't you?
太危险了 别去
It's dangerous, don't go.
- 我得去 - 去干嘛?
- I have to. - You have to what?
找死吗?
Get killed?
我不会等你
I won't wait for you.
那好 我叫甘兰直接送你回伦敦
Fine. Then I'll have Kamran send you direct to London.
你这顽固的死笨...
You dumb, stubborn, stupid...
这是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
你这死鬼
Back end of horse.
你叫我做死鬼?
Are you calling me a horse's ass?
我可能不会再见到你
I might never see you again.
你会的
You will.
我答应你
I promise.
生的鸦片 纽约市值五亿元
Raw opium. worth half a billion dollars on the streets of New York.
你们在干嘛? 卖鸦片吗?
What are you up to, selling dope?
小声点 那是雪豹集团的老板
Not so loud. That's the chief of the Snow Leopard Brotherhood.
是黄金月形地带最大的鸦片批发
The biggest opium dealer in the Golden Crescent.
我有时也跟他们做买卖
I work for them sometimes.
我不管俄罗斯人因我的子弹 还是他们的鸦片而死
I wouldn't care if the Russians die from my bullets or their opium.
而且 我们要钱买军火
Besides,we need the monev to buy arms.
基奥治
Georgi.
还有钻石
And the diamonds.
他安排俄罗斯人买高科技武器
He arranged for the Russians to buv high-tech weapons.
但他用那些钱买鸦片
But he's using that monev to buy opium.
几天就可以赚大钱...
He can turn a huge profit in days...
...同时也可以给俄罗斯提供军火
...and still provide the Russians with their arms.
- 除非... - 继续说
- Unless.... - Go on.
如果鸦片永远到不了呢?
If the opium never arrives?
雪豹集团不是容易对付的
The Brotherhood are very dangerous to cross.
- 俄罗斯入侵以来最大的交易 - 你不打算帮忙?
- Biggest deal since Russian invasion. - You won't help?
也许吧
Perhaps.
交易不会完成 除非俄国人付清费用后离开
If nothing is done till the Russians pay up and leave.
对 我要一些塑胶炸药和计时器
Right. I'll need some plastic explosives and a timer.
看看我可以做些什么
I'll see what I can do.
停住!
Halt!
去吧
Go.
詹姆斯被抓住了 我们得救他
James is trapped. You must help him.
他要承受风险
He's got to take his chances.
- 你欠他你的命 - 我无能为力
- You owe him your life. - There's nothing more I can do.
不 你能的
Yes,there is.
女人
Women.
费耶达上校
Colonel Fevador.
在这里等一下 我们会回来找你
Wait here. we'll come back for you.
别开枪! 别炸毁飞机
Don't shoot! Don't destroy the plane.
- 挡住跑道!  - 是!
- Block the runway! - Da!
那架运油车!
The tanker!
她在哪里?
Where is she?
我们得制止他!
We have to stop him!
卡拉
Kara.
别开枪! 你会击中飞机!
Don't shoot! You'll hit the plane!
- 卡拉!  - 我的天!
- Kara! - Oh, my God!
跳吧!
Jump!
- 你来了 接手吧 - 什么?
- Now that you're here,take over. - What?
抓紧 保持平衡
Hold this straight and level.
- 你去哪里?  - 拆掉炸弹
- Where are you going? - To defuse a bomb.
不要!
No!
求求你!
Please!
- 怎么了?  - 他拿了我的靴子
- What happened? - He got the boot.
接手 这次保持平衡
Take over. Hold it steady.
- 你去哪里?  - 投炸弹
- Where are you going? - To drop a bomb.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
燃料就快完了
We're losing fuel fast.
希望可以熬到巴基斯坦
I just hope we can make Pakistan.
没有地方可以着陆
There's no place to put down.
回去 上车 快!
Go in the back. Get in the jeep. Quickly!
系紧安全带!
Fasten your seat belt!
抓紧!
Hold on!
我知道卡拉奇最好的餐馆在哪里
I know a great restaurant in Karachi.
我可以在那里吃晚饭
We can just make dinner.
惠特克在地下
Whitaker's on the groundfloor.
科斯克夫在楼上一个房间里
Koskov is in one of theupstairs bedrooms.
你旁边的池边有个守卫
Guard in the pool area near you.
守卫离开 继续行动
Guard clear. Proceed.
等一下
Holdit.
他回来了
He's coming back.
去吧 詹姆斯 通话完毕
Go,James. Over and out.
他进去了
Well, he's in.
皮克特的任务该在墓地山脉完成 而不是在小圆山顶
Pickett's charge was up Cemetery Ridge, not Little Round Top.
我在重演先前的战事
I'm replaying the battle as I would have fought it.
米德虽然顽强 但他也很小心
Meade was tenacious, but he was cautious.
他错过了 在盖第斯堡撞死阿李的机会
He missed his chances to crush Lee at Gettvsburg.
我来找科斯克夫
I've come for Koskov.
只要我拿到鸦片...
Well, hell,you can have him...
...你马上可以带他走
...as soon as I get my opium.
- 现在鸦片在哪里?  - 化为乌有
- Now,where is it? - Up in smoke.
你烧毁了五亿元?
You burned up a half a billion bucks?
邦德 那真糟糕
Well,that's too bad, Bond.
你本来可以做一个富有的活人...
You know,you could have been a live rich man...
...而不是一个死了的穷人
...instead of a poor dead one.
你完蛋了 惠特克
You're finished,whitaker.
若俄罗斯不抓你 美国人也会
If the Russians don't get you, the Americans will.
不
No.
你知道 米德本来会多害 三万五千个人
You know, Meade should have taken another 35,000 casualties.
这样最后会发生暴动的
Could have ended the rebellion right there.
格兰会摆平它
Grant would have done it.
你已开了八枪 现在到我的八十枪了
You've had your eight. Now I'll have my 80.
抱歉 你的玩具枪 比不过我最先进的武器
Sorry to say,your popgun is no match for the latest body armor.
我早知道你会躲在...
Should have known you'd take refuge...
...英国威灵顿贪心汉背后
...behind that British vulture wellington.
你知道他买了德国雇佣兵...
You know he had to buv German mercenaries...
...来对付拿破伦的 是吗?
...to beat Napoleon, don't you?
我欠你的 邦德
I owed you that one, Bond.
他战败了
He met his waterloo.
普谢金上将
General Pushkin.
你还活着 真好!
Thank God you're still alive!
惠特克抓住我几个星期了
Whitaker has held me here for weeks.
谢谢你救了我 谢谢!
Thank you for rescuing me. Thank you!
带他乘下一班到莫斯科的航机
Put him on the next plane to Moscow.
谢谢 上将! 非常感谢
Thank you, general! Thank you so much.
放在外交邮袋里
In the diplomatic bag.
那卡拉呢?
What about Kara?
她也是背叛者
She is a defector too.
我们该怎么处里她?
What shall we do about her?
你要留在法国吗?
Are you going to stav in France now?
跟我来吧 介意我们离开一会吗?
Come with me, my dear. will you excuse us?
高戈上将 这是卡拉米劳维
General Gogol, Miss Kara Milovy.
非常精彩!
Magnificent!
希望你很快可以来莫斯科表演
I hope you can find time to play in Moscow very soon.
没问题 高戈上将现在在外交部工作
It's okay. General Gogol's now with their foreign service.
他会安排移民签证...
He's arranged an immigration visa...
...让你可以随时出入境
...so you can come and go as you like.
太好了!
Wonderful!
不好意思
Excuse me.
不要紧!
It's all right!
抱歉我们错过了音乐会 我们在机厂出了点问题
I'm sorry we missed the concert. we had some trouble at the airport.
你想也想不到
I can't imagine why.
高戈上将 你见过甘兰沙没有?
General Gogol, have you met Kamran Shah?
- 当然 - 詹姆斯在哪里?
- My pleasure. - Where's James?
可惜 他有任务到外国去了
Unhappily, he's on assignment abroad.
我很快就回来
I'll be with you shortly.
你以为我真的错过了音乐会?
You didn't think I'd miss this performance, did you?
哦 詹姆斯
Oh,James.